So my freshman year of college
خلال السنة الاولى لي في الجامعة
I signed up for an internship in the housing unit
لقد اشتركت في تدريب في الوحدة السكنية
at Greater Boston Legal Services.
في خدمات بوسطن القانونية.
Showed up the first day
حضرت في اليوم الأول
ready to make coffee and photocopies,
مستعدة لعمل القهوة و النسخ,
but was paired with this righteous, deeply inspired attorney
ولكن تم إرفاقي مع هذا المحامي الصالح، والشديد الحماسة
named Jeff Purcell,
اسمة جيف بورسيل،
who thrust me onto the front lines
دفعني لاكون علي الخطوط الأمامية
from the very first day.
منذ اليوم الاول؛
And over the course of nine months
و على مدى تسعة اشهر
I had the chance
قد سنحت لي الفرصة
to have dozens of conversations
لإجراء العشرات من المحادثات
with low-income families in Boston
مع عائلات من الدخل المحدود في بوسطن
who would come in presenting with housing issues,
الذين يأتون لعرض قضايا الإسكان الخاصة بهم،
but always had an underlying health issue.
ولكن كان دائما هناك قضية اساسية تتعلق بالصحة .
So I had a client who came in,
و كان لدي موكلي الذي جاء،
about to be evicted because he hasn't paid his rent.
لأنه على وشك أن يطرد لانه لم يدفع ايجار منزله.
But he hasn't paid his rent, of course,
لكنه لم يدفع ايجاره ,بالطبع,
because he's paying for his HIV medication
لأنه كان يغطي تكاليف الادوية لمرض الايدز الذي لديه
and just can't afford both.
فهو لا يستطيع ان يتحمل تكاليف الاثنين معا.
We had moms who would come in,
كان لدينا امهات كن يأتين,
daughter has asthma,
ابنتي لديها ربو,
wakes up covered in cockroaches every morning.
تستيقظ كل صباح مغطاة بالصراصير,
And one of our litigation strategies
وإحدى استراتيجيات التقاضي لدينا
was actually to send me into the home of these clients
كانت في الواقع تقوم على إرسالي إلى داخل بيوت هؤلاء الموكلين
with these large glass bottles.
مع هذه القوارير الزجاجية الكبيرة.
And I would collect the cockroaches,
أود أن اجمع الصراصير،
hot glue-gun them to this poster board
و الصقهم بالصمغ على لوح كارتون
that we'd bring to court for our cases.
و كنا نحضرها و نقدمها إلى المحكمة في القضايا.
And we always won
و كنا نفوز دائما
because the judges were just so grossed out.
لان القضاة يقرفون من رؤيتها.
Far more effective, I have to say,
أكثر فعالية بكثير، يجب أن أقول،
than anything I later learned in law school.
من أي شيء آخر تعلمته فيما بعد في مدرسة القانون.
But over the course of these nine months,
لكن خلال مدة التسعة اشهر,
I grew frustrated with feeling
نما شعوري بالاحباط و شعرت
like we were intervening too far downstream
و كأننا نحن أيضا كنا نتدخل كثيرا
in the lives of our clients --
في حياة موكلينا --
that by the time they came to us,
لحدود أنه بحلول الوقت الذي جاؤوا لنا،
they were already in crisis.
كانوا بالفعل في أزمة.
And at the end of my freshman year of college,
وعند نهاية العام الاول لي كطالبة في الكلية،
I read an article about the work
قرأت مقالا عن العمل
that Dr. Barry Zuckerman was doing
الذي كان الدكتور باري زوكرمان يقوم به
as Chair of Pediatrics
بصفته رئيس طب الأطفال
at Boston Medical Center.
في المركز الطبي في بوسطن.
And his first hire was a legal services attorney
وكانت وظيفته الأولى كمحام في الخدمات القانونية
to represent the patients.
لتمثيل المرضى.
So I called Barry,
لذلك اتصلت بباري,
and with his blessing, in October 1995
و بمباركته, في تشرين الاول في عام ١٩٩٥
walked into the waiting room
دخلت الى غرفة الانتظار
of the pediatrics clinic at Boston Medical Center.
في عيادة الاطفال في المركز الطبي في بوسطن.
I'll never forget,
لن انسى ابدا,
the TVs played this endless reel of cartoons.
كان التلفاز يعرض حلقات لا نهاية لها من افلام الكرتون
And the exhaustion of mothers
و التعب المضني للامهات
who had taken two, three, sometimes four buses
اللواتي اخذن اثنان, ثلاثة, في بعض الاحيان أربعة باصات
to bring their child to the doctor
ليجلبن اطفالهن للطبيب
was just palpable.
كان واضحا تماما.
The doctors, it seemed,
الاطباء, كان ظاهرا,
never really had enough time for all the patients,
لم يكن لديهم في الواقع ما يكفي من الوقت لجميع المرضى،
try as they might.
يحاولون على ما يقدرون.
And over the course of six months,
و على مدى ستة اشهر,
I would corner them in the hallway
كنت احاصرهم في الردهة
and ask them a sort of naive but fundamental question:
و اسألهم بعض الاسئلة الساذجة لكن سؤالي الاساسي كان:
"If you had unlimited resources,
"اذا كان لديك موارد غير محدودة،
what's the one thing you would give your patients?"
ما هو الشيء الوحيد الذي ستعطيه لمرضاك؟ "
And I heard the same story again and again,
وسمعت نفس القصة مرارا وتكرارا،
a story we've heard hundreds of times since then.
قصة سمعناها مئات المرات منذ ذلك الحين.
They said, "Every day we have patients that come into the clinic --
قالوا: "في كل يوم لدينا العديد من المرضى الذين يأتون الى العيادة
child has an ear infection,
طفل مصاب بالتهاب في الأذن،
I prescribe antibiotics.
اوصف له المضادات الحيوية.
But the real issue is there's no food at home.
لكن القضية الحقيقية هو عدم وجود الطعام في المنزل.
The real issue
القضية الحقيقية
is that child is living with 12 other people
ان هذا الطفل يعيش مع 12 شخصا آخر
in a two-bedroom apartment.
في شقة مكونة من غرفتي نوم.
And I don't even ask about those issues
وأنا لا أسأل حتى حول تلك القضايا
because there's nothing I can do.
لأنه لا يوجد شيء يمكن أن أقوم به.
I have 13 minutes with each patient.
لدي 13 دقيقة مع كل مريض.
Patients are piling up in the clinic waiting room.
المرضى متراكمون في غرفة الانتظار في العيادة.
I have no idea where the nearest food pantry is.
ليس لدي أي فكرة عن مكان أقرب مخزن للمواد الغذائية.
And I don't even have any help."
وأنا لا استطيع الحصول على أي مساعدة ".
In that clinic, even today,
في تلك العيادة، كل يوم
there are two social workers
يتواجد هناك اثنين من الأخصائيين الاجتماعيين
for 24,000 pediatric patients,
ل24000 طفل من الأطفال المرضى،
which is better than a lot of the clinics out there.
وهو افضل من الكثير من العيادات هناك.
So Health Leads was born of these conversations --
هكذا ولدت "Health Leads" من هذه الأحاديث -
a simple model
نموذج بسيط
where doctors and nurses
حيث الأطباء والممرضات
can prescribe nutritious food,
يمكن أن يصفوا الأطعمة المغذية،
heat in the winter
والحرارة في فصل الشتاء
and other basic resources for their patients
والموارد الأساسية الأخرى لمرضاهم
the same way they prescribe medication.
بنفس الطريقة التي يصفون فيها الدواء.
Patients then take their prescriptions
ثم يأخذ المرضى وصفاتهم الطبية
to our desk in the clinic waiting room
الى مكتبنا في غرفة الإنتظار عند عيادة الطبيب
where we have a core of well-trained college student advocates
حيث لدينا مجموعة أساسية من الطلاب الجامعيين المدربين تدريبا جيدا
who work side by side with these families
الذين يعملون جنبا الى جنب مع هذه العائلات
to connect them out
لربطهم
to the existing landscape of community resources.
بالمشهد الحالي لموارد المجتمع.
So we began with a card table in the clinic waiting room --
لذلك ابتدأنا بوضع طاولة للبطاقات في غرقة الانتظار للعيادة
totally lemonade stand style.
كطاولة بيع عصير الليمون
But today we have a thousand college student advocates
لكن اليوم اصبح لدينا ألف طالب جامعي يسلهمون
who are working to connect nearly 9,000 patients and their families
في العمل من أجل ربط ما يقرب من 9000 من المرضى وعائلاتهم
with the resources that they need to be healthy.
مع الموارد التي يحتاجون إليها للتمتع بالصحة.
So 18 months ago
هكذا قبل 18 شهرا
I got this email that changed my life.
وصلت هذه الرسالة التي غيرت حياتي.
And the email was from Dr. Jack Geiger,
وكان البريد الإلكتروني من الدكتور جاك جيجر،
who had written to congratulate me on Health Leads
الذي كان قد كتب لي لتهنئتي ب Health Leads
and to share, as he said,
وليشاركني ، كما قال،
a bit of historical context.
قليلا من السياق التاريخي.
In 1965 Dr. Geiger founded
في عام 1965 أسس الدكتور جيجر
one of the first two community health centers in this country,
واحد من أول مركزين من مراكزالصحة المجتمعية في هذا البلد،
in a brutally poor area in the Mississippi Delta.
في منطقة فقيرة وقاسية في دلتا الميسيسيبي.
And so many of his patients came in
وكان العديد من مرضاه
presenting with malnutrition
يعانون من سوء التغذية
that be began prescribing food for them.
حيث بدأ بوصف الطعام لهم.
And they would take these prescriptions to the local supermarket,
وبدأوا يأخذون هذه الوصفات إلى السوبر ماركت المحلية،
which would fill them
حيث يقومون بملئ الوصفة
and then charge the pharmacy budget of the clinic.
و التكلفة تدفع من ميزانية العيادة.
And when the Office of Economic Opportunity in Washington, D.C. --
وعندما اكتشف مكتب الفرص الاقتصادية في واشنطن -
which was funding Geiger's clinic --
والذي كان ممولا لعيادة جيجر -
found out about this,
هذا الموضوع،
they were furious.
كانوا شديدي الغضب.
And they sent this bureaucrat down
وأرسلوا هذا البيروقراطي الى العيادة
to tell Geiger that he was expected to use their dollars
ليقول لغايغر الذي كان من المتوقع ان يستخدم دولاراتهم
for medical care --
من اجل الرعاية الطبية -
to which Geiger famously and logically responded,
والتي استجاب لها جيجر وبصورة منطقية ،
"The last time I checked my textbooks,
"إن آخر مرة لي حين راجعت كتبي مدرسية،
the specific therapy for malnutrition was food."
كان العلاج المحدد لسوء التغذية هو الغذاء".
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
So when I got this email from Dr. Geiger,
هكذا عندما وصلت هذه الرسالة من الدكتور جيجر،
I knew I was supposed to be proud
عرفت ان على ان اكون فخورة
to be part of this history.
بكوني جزء من هذا التاريخ
But the truth is
لكن الحقيقة هي
I was devastated.
اني شعرت بحزن.
Here we are,
ها نحن,
45 years after Geiger has prescribed food for his patients,
بعد 45 عاما من الفترة التي وصف جيجر بها الغذاء لمرضاه،
and I have doctors telling me,
و هناك الأطباء يقولون لي،
"On those issues, we practice a 'don't ask, don't tell' policy."
"في تلك القضايا، ونحن نمارس سياسية 'لا تسأل، لا تخبر'".
Forty-five years after Geiger,
خمسة واربعين عاما بعد جيجر،
Health Leads has to reinvent
مضت لإعادة اختراع Health Leads
the prescription for basic resources.
لوصفة طبية للموارد الأساسية.
So I have spent hours upon hours
لقد قضيت ساعات وساعات
trying to make sense of this weird Groundhog Day.
في محاولة لفهم المنطق وراء يوم جرذ الأرض الغريب.
How is it that if for decades
كيف يتم ذلك إذا كان لعدة عقود
we had a pretty straightforward tool for keeping patients,
كان لدينا أداة واضحة للحفاظ على المرضى،
and especially low-income patients, healthy,
وخصوصا ذوي الدخل المنخفض من المرضى، أصحاء،
that we didn't use it?
ولكننا لم نستخدمها؟
If we know what it takes to have a healthcare system
إذا كنا نعرف ما يلزم ليكون هناك نظام للرعاية الصحية
rather than a sick-care system,
بدلا من نظام مريض لرعاية المرضى،
why don't we just do it?
لماذا لا نفعل سوى ذلك؟
These questions, in my mind,
هذه الأسئلة، في رأيي،
are not hard because the answers are complicated,
ليست صعبة لأن الإجابات معقدة ،
they are hard because they require that we be honest with ourselves.
أنها صعبة لأنها تتطلب منا أن نكون صادقين مع أنفسنا.
My belief is that it's almost too painful
اعتقادي هو أنه من المؤلم للغاية
to articulate our aspirations for our healthcare system,
ان نقوم بالتعبير عن تطلعاتنا لنظام الرعاية الصحية لدينا،
or even admit that we have any at all.
أو حتى الاعتراف بأن لدينا واحد على الإطلاق.
Because if we did,
لأنه إذا فعلنا،
they would be so removed
فسيكون الأثر إزالته
from our current reality.
من واقعنا الحالي.
But that doesn't change my belief
ولكن هذا لا يغير قناعتي
that all of us, deep inside,
كل واحد منا، في عمقنا،
here in this room and across this country,
هنا في هذه القاعة وعبر هذا البلد،
share a similar set of desires.
نتقاسم مجموعة مماثلة من الرغبات.
That if we are honest with ourselves
هذا إذا كنا صادقين مع أنفسنا
and listen quietly,
ونستمع بهدوء،
that we all harbor
أننا جميعا عى نفس المركب
one fiercely held aspiration for our healthcare:
الذي عقد بشدة على طموح الرعاية الصحية لدينا
that it keep us healthy.
الذي يسهر على جعلنا اصحاء
This aspiration that our healthcare keep us healthy
هذا الطموح أن الرعاية الصحية لدينا يجب ان تبقينا اصحاء
is an enormously powerful one.
هو طموح قوي جدا.
And the way I think about this
والطريقة التي أفكر بها بذلك
is that healthcare is like any other system.
هو أن الرعاية الصحية مثل أي نظام آخر.
It's just a set of choices that people make.
فهي مجرد مجموعة من الخيارات التي يقوم بها الناس.
What if we decided
ماذا لو قررنا
to make a different set of choices?
ان نختار مجموعة مختلفة من الخيارات؟
What if we decided to take all the parts of healthcare
ماذا لو قررنا اتخاذ جميع أجزاء الرعاية الصحية
that have drifted away from us
التي انجرفت بعيدا عنا
and stand firm and say, "No.
ونقف بحزم ونقول "لا.
These things are ours.
هذه الأشياء هي في مصلحتنا.
They will be used for our purposes.
وسيتم استخدامها لأغراضنا.
They will be used to realize
ستستخدم لتحقيق
our aspiration"?
طموحنا"؟
What if everything we needed
ماذا لو كان كل ما نحتاجه
to realize our aspiration for healthcare
لتحقيق طموحنا للرعاية الصحية
was right there in front of us
يقف امام اعيننا
just waiting to be claimed?
ينتظر من سيطالب به؟
So that's where Health Leads began.
هذا هو المكان الذي بدأت Health Leads فيه .
We started with the prescription pad --
بدأت مع منصة وصفة طبية -
a very ordinary piece of paper --
قطعة من الورق العادي جدا -
and we asked, not what do patients need to get healthy --
وطلبنا، ليس ما يحتاج المرضى للحصول على الصحة -
antibiotics, an inhaler, medication --
المضادات الحيوية، والاستنشاق، والأدوية -
but what do patients need to be healthy,
ولكن ما يحتاج اليه المرضى للتمتع بالصحة،
to not get sick in the first place?
لعدم المرض في المقام الأول؟
And we chose to use the prescription
واخترنا استخدام الوصفة الطبية
for that purpose.
لذلك الغرض.
So just a few miles from here
هكذا بضعة أميال من هنا
at Children's National Medical Center,
في مركز طب الاطفال الوطني
when patients come into the doctor's office,
عندما يأتي المرضى لعيادة الطبيب,
they're asked a few questions.
يطرح عليهم بعض الاسئلة.
They're asked, "Are you running out of food at the end of the month?
يطلب منهم، "هل نفذ الطعام بنهاية الشهر؟
Do you have safe housing?"
هل لديك السكن الآمن؟ "
And when the doctor begins the visit,
وعندما يبدأ الطبيب في الزيارة،
she knows height, weight, is there food at home,
قالت انها تعرف الطول والوزن، هل هناك طعام في المنزل،
is the family living in a shelter.
وهل تعيش العائلة في مأوى.
And that not only leads to a better set of clinical choices,
وهذا ليس فقط يؤدي إلى أفضل مجموعة من الخيارات الطبية،
but the doctor can also prescribe those resources for the patient,
ولكن الطبيب يستطيع وصف هذه الموارد للمرضى أيضا ،
using Health Leads like any other sub-specialty referral.
و ذلك باستخدام Health Leads كأي إحالة فرعية متخصصة أخرى.
The problem is,
المشكلة هي,
once you get a taste of what it's like
بمجرد ان تدرك ما يعنيه
to realize your aspiration for healthcare,
تحقيق الطموح للحصول على الرعاية الصحية،
you want more.
فانك تصبح تريد أكثر من ذلك.
So we thought,
هكذا كنا نتصور الأمر،
if we can get individual doctors
إذا استطعنا الحصول على أطباء
to prescribe these basic resources for their patients,
لوصف هذه الموارد الأساسية لمرضاهم،
could we get an entire healthcare system
يمكن أن نحصل على نظام الرعاية الصحية بأكمله
to shift its presumption?
لتحويل الأحكام المسبقة ؟
And we gave it a shot.
و اعطيناه الفرصة.
So now at Harlem Hospital Center
الآن في مركز مستشفى هارليم
when patients come in with an elevated body mass index,
عندما يأتي المرضى مع ارتفاع مؤشر كتلة الجسم،
the electronic medical record
السجل الإلكتروني الطبي
automatically generates a prescription for Health Leads.
يولد تلقائيا وصفة طبية ل. Health Leads
And our volunteers can then work with them
ثم يمكن لمتطوعينا العمل معهم
to connect patients to healthy food and excercise programs
لربطهم بالبرامج الغذائية والصحية و التمارين الرياضية
in their communities.
في مجتمعاتهم.
We've created a presumption
لقد انشأنا الافتراض
that if you're a patient at that hospital
إذا كنت مريضا في تلك المستشفى
with an elevated BMI,
مع مؤشر كتلة الجسم المرتفع،
the four walls of the doctor's office
الجدران الأربعة لمكتب الطبيب
probably aren't going to give you everything
ربما لن تعطيك كل شيء
you need to be healthy.
تحتاجه للتمتع بالصحة.
You need more.
انت تحتاج اكثر من ذلك.
So on the one hand,
من جهة،
this is just a basic recoding
هذا هو مجرد إعادة ترميز
of the electronic medical record.
للسجل الطبي الالكتروني.
And on the other hand,
ومن جهة أخرى،
it's a radical transformation
انه تحول جذري
of the electronic medical record
في السجل الطبي الإلكتروني
from a static repository of diagnostic information
من مستودع ثابت من المعلومات التشخيصية
to a health promotion tool.
لأداة لترويج الصحة.
In the private sector,
في القطاع الخاص,
when you squeeze that kind of additional value
عند الضغط على هذا النوع من القيمة الإضافية
out of a fixed-cost investment,
من الاستثمار الثابت من حيث التكلفة،
it's called a billion-dollar company.
هذا يدعى شركة بقيمة مليار دولار.
But in my world,
ولكن في عالمي،
it's called reduced obesity and diabetes.
هذا يدعى انخفاض البدانة ومرض السكري .
It's called healthcare --
هذا يدعى الرعاية الصحية --
a system where doctors can prescribe solutions
نظام حيث يستطيع الأطباء وصف الحلول
to improve health,
لتحسين الصحة,
not just manage disease.
ليس فقط تخفيف المرض.
Same thing in the clinic waiting room.
نفس الشيء في غرفة الإنتظارلعيادة الطبيب .
So every day in this country
هكذا كل يوم في هذا البلد
three million patients
ثلاثة ملايين مريض
pass through about 150,000 clinic waiting rooms in this country.
يمرون عبر حوالي 150،000غرفة انتظار في هذا البلد.
And what do they do when they're there?
وماذا يفعلون عندما يكونون هناك؟
They sit, they watch the goldfish in the fish tank,
يجلسون و يشاهدون سمكة ذهبية في حوض للأسماك،
they read extremely old copies
يقرأون من النسخ القديمة للغاية
of Good Housekeeping magazine.
مجلة التدبير المنزلي الجيد.
But mostly we all just sit there forever, waiting.
ولكن الأغلب أننا جميعا نجلس إلى الأبد، في انتظار.
How did we get here
كيف وصلنا هنا
where we devote hundreds of acres and thousands of hours
حيث نكرس مئات الأفدنة ، والآلاف من ساعات
to waiting?
للانتظار؟
What if we had a waiting room
ماذا لو كان لدينا غرفة انتظار
where you don't just sit when you're sick,
حيث لا نجلس فقط عندما نكون مرضى،
but where you go to get healthy.
لكن حيث نذهب للحصول على صحة جيدة.
If airports can become shopping malls
إذا يمكن أن تصبح المطارات مراكز تسوق
and McDonald's can become playgrounds,
ويمكن لماكدونالدز أن تصبح ملاعب،
surely we can reinvent the clinic waiting room.
بالتأكيد يمكننا إعادة ابتكار غرفة الإنتظار.
And that's what Health Leads has tried to do,
وهذا ما حاولت Health Leads القيام به،
to reclaim that real estate and that time
لاستعادة تلك العقارات، والوقت
and to use it as a gateway
واستخدامها كبوابة
to connect patients
لربط المرضى
to the resources they need to be healthy.
بالموارد التي يحتاجون إليها للتمتع بالصحة.
So it's a brutal winter in the Northeast,
لذلك فصل الشتاء قاسي في شمال شرق البلاد،
your kid has asthma, your heat just got turned off,
ابنك لديه مرض الربو, التدفئة توقفت في المنزل،
and of course you're in the waiting room of the ER,
وطبعا انت في غرفة الانتظار لغرفة الطوارى،
because the cold air triggered your child's asthma.
وذلك لأن الهواء البارد أثار الربو عند طفلك.
But what if instead of waiting for hours anxiously,
ولكن ماذا لو بدلا من الانتظار لساعات طويلة بفارغ الصبر،
the waiting room became the place
أصبحت غرفة الانتظار المكان
where Health Leads turned your heat back on?
حيث اتاحت لك فيه Health Leads ان تستعيد فيه دفئك؟
And of course all of this requires
و بالطبع كل هذا يتطلب
a broader workforce.
قوى عاملة اوسع.
But if we're creative, we already have that too.
ولكن إذا كنا مبدعين، لدينا بالفعل ذلك أيضا.
We know that our doctors and nurses
نحن نعلم أن لدينا أطباء وممرضات
and even social workers
والعاملين الاجتماعيين حتى
aren't enough,
ليسوا بالكفاية,
that the ticking minutes of health care
حتى أن الدقائق المخصصة للرعاية الصحية
are too constraining.
مقيدة ايضا.
Health just takes more time.
الصحة تتطلب المزيد من الوقت.
It requires a non-clinical army
أنها تتطلب جيشا غير طبي
of community health workers and case managers
من العاملين في صحة المجتمع ومدراء الحالات
and many others.
و المزيد من الاشخاص.
What if a small part of that next healthcare workforce
ماذا لو كان الجزء الصغير من القوى العاملة الصحية المقبلة
were the 11 million college students in this country?
11مليون طالب/ طالبة جامعة في هذا البلد؟
Unencumbered by clinical responsibilities,
غير مرتبطين بالمسؤوليات الطبية،
unwilling to take no for an answer
وغير مستعدين لاستخدام "لا" كإجابة
from those bureaucracies
من تلك البيروقراطية
that tend to crush patients,
التي تميل إلى سحق المرضى،
and with an unparalleled ability
ومع قدرة لا مثيل لها
for information retrieval
لاسترجاع المعلومات
honed through years of using Google.
شحذت من سنوات من استخدام غوغل.
Now lest you think it improbable
الآن وحتى لا تظنوا أنه من غير المحتمل
that a college volunteer
ان يكون المتطوعين الجامعيين
can make this kind of commitment,
قادرين على أن يقدموا هذا النوع من الالتزام،
I have two words for you:
عندي كلمتين لكم:
March Madness.
مارسوا الجنون.
The average NCAA Division I men's basketball player
يخصص لاعب كرة سلة في الرابطة الوطنية للرياضات الجماعية في الشعبة الأولى للرجال
dedicates 39 hours a week to his sport.
متوسط 39 ساعة في الأسبوع لرياضته.
Now we may think that's good or bad,
الآن قد نعتقد انه شيء جيد او سيئ،
but in either case it's real.
ولكن في كلتا الحالتين انها حقيقية.
And Health Leads is based on the presumption
وتستند Health Leads على افتراض
that for too long
أنه لفترة طويلة جدا
we have asked too little of our college students
طلبنا القليل جدا من طلاب الجامعات لدينا
when it comes to real impact in vulnerable communities.
عندما يتعلق الأمر بالأثر الحقيقي في المجتمعات المعرضة للخطر.
College sports teams say,
الفرق الرياضية الجامعية تقول،
"We're going to take dozens of hours
"نحن سنقوم باتخاذ عشرات الساعات
at some field across campus at some ungodly hour of the morning
" في احد الملاعب في الحرم الجامعي في ساعات الفجر من الصباح
and we're going to measure your performance, and your team's performance,
ونحن في طريقنا لقياس الأداء الخاص بك، وأداء الفريق الخاص بك،
and if you don't measure up or you don't show up,
وإذا كنت لا ترقى أو أنك لا تظهر،
we're going to cut you off the team.
سنقوم بابعادك من الفريق.
But we'll make huge investments
لكن سيتعين علينا القيام باستثمارات ضخمة
in your training and development,
في التدريب الخاص بك وتنميتك،
and we'll give you an extraordinary community of peers."
وسنعطيك مجتمع استثنائي من الأقران ".
And people line up out the door
ويصطف الناس خارج الباب
just for the chance to be part of it.
فقط للحصول على فرصة ليكونوا جزءا منه.
So our feeling is,
ما نشعر به،
if it's good enough for the rugby team,
انه اذا كان جيد بما فيه الكفاية لفريق لعبة الرجبي،
it's good enough for health and poverty.
فانه جيد بما فيه الكفاية من أجل الصحة والفقر.
Health Leads too recruits competitively,
Health Leads تجند بشكل تنافسي ،
trains intensively,
و تدرب بشكل مكثف،
coaches professionally,
تدريبا مهنيا،
demands significant time,
يتطلب وقتا كبيرا،
builds a cohesive team
وتبني فريق متماسك
and measures results --
و تقيس النتائج. -
a kind of Teach for America for healthcare.
وهو نوع من التعليم لأمريكا للرعاية الصحية.
Now in the top 10 cities in the U.S.
الآن أكبر 10 مدن في الولايات المتحدة
with the largest number of Medicaid patients,
مع أكبر عدد من المرضى المعتمدين على المعونة الطبية،
each of those has at least 20,000 college students.
كل من هذه المدن لديها ما لا يقل عن 20000 طالب جامعي.
New York alone has half a million college students.
نيويورك وحدها لديها نصف مليون من طلبة الجامعة.
And this isn't just a sort of short-term workforce
وهذه ليست مجرد نوع من القوى العاملة على المدى القصير
to connect patients to basic resources,
لربط المرضى المعتمدين على الموارد الأساسية،
it's a next generation healthcare leadership pipeline
انها الجيل القادم القيادي للرعاية الصحية
who've spent two, three, four years
الذي قضى اثنان، ثلاثة، أربعة أعوام
in the clinic waiting room
في غرفة الانتظار للعيادة
talking to patients about their most basic health needs.
يتحدثون مع المرضى عن حاجاتهم الصحية الأساسية.
And they leave with the conviction,
ويغادرون مع القناعة،
the ability and the efficacy
والقدرة والكفاءة
to realize our most basic aspirations for health care.
في تحقيق احتياجاتنا الأساسية و تطلعاتنا للرعاية الصحية.
And the thing is, there's thousands of these folks already out there.
والشيء هو، انه يوجد الآلاف من هؤلاء الناس بالفعل هناك.
So Mia Lozada is Chief Resident of Internal Medicine
لذا ميا لوزادا والتي هي المقيمة الرئيسة للطب الباطني
at UCSF Medical Center,
في المركز الطبي لمستشفى سان فرانسيسكو،
but for three years as an undergraduate
ولكن لمدة ثلاث سنوات باعتبارها طالبة جامعية
she was a Health Leads volunteer
كانت احدى المتطوعين في Health Leads
in the clinic waiting room at Boston Medical Center.
في غرفة الانتظار في عيادة مركز بوسطن الطبي.
Mia says, "When my classmates write a prescription,
ميا تقول "عندما يكتب زملائي وصفة طبية،
they think their work is done.
فانهم يعتقدون ان عملهم قد تم.
When I write a prescription,
عندما اكتب انا وصفة طبية،
I think, can the family read the prescription?
فانني افكر، هل يمكن للأسرة قراءة وصفة طبية؟
Do they have transportation to the pharmacy?
هل لديهم وسائل النقل للوصول للصيدلية؟
Do they have food to take with the prescription?
هل لديهم طعام لتناوله مع الوصفة الطبية؟
Do they have insurance to fill the prescription?
هل لديهم تأمين صحي لملء الوصفة الطبية؟
Those are the questions I learned at Health Leads,
هذه هي الأسئلة التي تعلمتها في ، Health Leads
not in medical school."
وليس في كلية الطب ".
Now none of these solutions --
الآن أيا من هذه الحلول -
the prescription pad, the electronic medical record,
الوصفة الطبية، السجل الإلكتروني الطبي،
the waiting room,
غرفة الانتظار,
the army of college students --
جيش الطلبة الجامعيين,
are perfect.
في منتهى الكمال.
But they are ours for the taking --
لكنهم لنا لنأخذ -
simple examples
امثلة بسيطة
of the vast under-utilized healthcare resources
من الموارد الهائلة للرعاية الصحية غير المستغلة
that, if we reclaimed and redeployed,
التي، اذا استصلحت واعيد نشرها،
could realize our most basic aspiration
يمكن أن تحقق طموحنا الاساسي
of healthcare.
للرعاية الصحية.
So I had been at Legal Services for about nine months
لذا كنت عند الخدمات القانونية لحوالي تسعة أشهر
when this idea of Health Leads started percolating in my mind.
عندما وردت في خاطري فكرة Health Leads
And I knew I had to tell Jeff Purcell, my attorney,
وكنت أعرف أنه كان علي أن أخبر جيف بورسيل المحامي الخاص بي،
that I needed to leave.
أنني يجب أن أغادر.
And I was so nervous,
و كنت متوترة جدا,
because I thought he was going to be disappointed in me
لأني اعتقدت اني كنت على وشك أن اشهد خيبة الأمل في نفسي
for abandoning our clients for some crazy idea.
للتخلي عن موكلينا من اجل فكرة مجنونة.
And I sat down with him and I said,
وجلست معه وقلت:
"Jeff, I have this idea
"جيف، لدي هذه الفكرة
that we could mobilize college students
حيث سنتمكن من تحريك طلاب الجامعات
to address patients' most basic health needs."
لتلبية احتياجات المرضى الصحية الاساسية."
And I'll be honest,
وسأكون صادقة،
all I wanted was for him to not be angry at me.
كل ما اردته هو أن لا يكون غاضبا علي.
But he said this,
لكنه قال،
"Rebecca, when you have a vision,
" ريبيكا، عندما يكون لديك رؤية،
you have an obligation to realize that vision.
فان لديك واجب لتحقيق تلك الرؤية.
You must pursue that vision."
يجب عليك متابعة تنفيذ هذه الرؤية".
And I have to say, I was like "Whoa.
وكنت أود أن أقول، مثل "قف.
That's a lot of pressure."
هذا الكثير من الضغط."
I just wanted a blessing,
أردت فقط مباركة،
I didn't want some kind of mandate.
أنا لم أرد نوعا من الإلزام.
But the truth is
لكن الحقيقة هي
I've spent every waking minute nearly since then
انني قضيت كل لحظة استيقاظ تقريبا منذ ذلك الحين
chasing that vision.
اطارد تلك الرؤية.
I believe that we all have a vision
وأعتقد أن لدينا جميعا رؤية
for healthcare in this country.
للرعاية الصحية في هذا البلد.
I believe that at the end of the day
وأعتقد أنه في نهاية اليوم
when we measure our healthcare,
عندما نقيس رعايتنا الصحية,
it will not be by the diseases cured,
فإنها لن تكون عن طريق الشفاء من الأمراض،
but by the diseases prevented.
بل بالوقاية منها,
It will not be by the excellence of our technologies
فإنه لن يكون من جانب تميز تقنياتنا
or the sophistication of our specialists,
أو مستوى التطور التقني للمتخصصين لدينا،
but by how rarely we needed them.
ولكن عبر قلة إحتياجنا لهم للإستشفاء.
And most of all,
والأهم من ذلك كله،
I believe that when we measure healthcare,
أعتقد أنه عندما نقيس الرعاية الصحية،
it will be, not by what the system was,
سيكون، ليس من خلال النظام الكائن،
but by what we chose it to be.
بل بما اخترناه أن يكون.
Thank you.
شكرا لكم.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)